A Finding Aid to the Nancy Spero Papers, 1940s-2009, in the Archives of American Art AAA.spernanc
Archives of American Art
- Subject Files, circa 1950-2009; Series 5; 12.6 Linear feet Boxes 6-18, 29, RD 30
  - Images, Source Material, 2000s; undated; Oversized material housed in Box 29. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - "Imagine Iraq: A Staged Reading of Works in Progress", 2001 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - "In the Spirit of Martin: The Living Legacy of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr." (2002 January-2004 March), Smithsonian Institution Traveling Exhibition Service, 2000-2001 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - "Inside the Visible" (1996-January 16-April 21), The Institute of Contemporary Art, Boston, 1995-1996 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Intercambios Culturales de El Salvador, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Jack Tilton Gallery, 1994-2002 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Jacobi Medical Center, Percent for Art, undated; 2001 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Japan, 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Jewish Community Center Swimming Pool, Mosaic Proposal, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Jewish Cultural Achievement Awards, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - The Jewish Museum, New York, 1993-2008 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Jewish Museum, Vienna, 1995-circa 2001 (Box 11, Folder 27-28)
  - Josh Baer Gallery, undated; 1985-1994 (Box 11, Folder 29-32)
  - Josh Baer Gallery, To Be Resolved, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Judson Art Warehouse, undated; 1993-1997 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Judson Art Warehouse, Additional Room, 1996-1997 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Judson Art Warehouse, Codex Artaud XXX and XXXI Mystery (photocopies, 1985-1987), 1997 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Jurgen Becker Galerie, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Kingsboro Community College, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Kunsthalle zu Kiel, 1998-2008 (Box 11, Folder 39-41)
  - Kunsthallen Brandts Klaedefabrik, "Dialogue with the Other" (1994 June 18-September 12) (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Kunsthaus Bregenz, 1995-1996 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Kunstichting Kanaal, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - "Kwangju Biennale" (2000), 1996-2000 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - "Language and Utopia in 20th Century Art: 1913-1968" (2000), Palais des Beaux-Arts de Bruxelles, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Lawrence Oliver Gallery, 1987-1994 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Lectures/Panels, 2000-2001 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Legendary Women Foundation, 1997-1998 (Box 12, Folder 8-9)
  - "Leon Golub and Nancy Spero: War and Memory" (1994-1995), American Center, Paris and List Visual Arts Center, M.I.T., 1994-1996; Includes 1 videocassette (VHS) (Box 12, Folder 10-11)
  - L'Evidence Cover, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Lewis and Clark College, Gallery of Contemporary Art, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Lincoln Center Redevelopment Conflict, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Lippard Vietnam Show, circa 1989 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Ljublijana, Slovenia, 1993-2007 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Lodz Biennale Project, 2004-2006 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - "Look Out!" (2000), Touring Exhibition (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Lotringer, Sylvere, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Lovers XVII, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Madrid Project, 1990-1991 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Main Line Art Center, "Printmaking 2010" (2010 February-March), 2009 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Mary Washington College, "Nancy Spero: Sheela Does Fredericksburg" (2000 October 5-December 15), 2000-2001 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, "Nancy Spero: Works Since 1950" (1988 October 7-December 4) (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Mayer, Renata and Gabriel, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Maypole Research, 2001-2002 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - McCord, Susan, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - McEvillevy, Thomas, circa 1980s-2006 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Mendieta, Ana, 1985-2007; Includes 2 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 12, Folder 29-30)
  - Mesarosis Gallery, West Virginia University, 24th Southern Graphics Council Conference, 1995-1996 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Metropolitan Transit Authority (MTA) Project, 66th Street/Lincoln Center Subway Station, Artemis, Acrobats, Divas and Dancers (Box 12)
    - Contract, 1997-2000 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Financial, 1997-2001 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Fritzi [Massery], The Diva, 1997-2000 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Images, circa 1997-circa 2001 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Miscellaneous, undated; 1997-2002 (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Party, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Photo Permit, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Pusan, Korea, Exhibition, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Resource Material re: Dancers, circa 1990s; 6 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
    - Statement, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Subway Plans, circa 1997-circa 2001 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Subway Station Photographs, circa 1999 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - UBS Gallery Exhibition (2005 June-September 9) (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Work in Progress, 1999-2002; 4 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 13, Folder 7-8)
  - Meyer, Rick [Ulrich] and Harriet, 1995-2006; Includes 1 videocassette (VHS) (Box 13, Folder 9-10)
  - Miami University, Ohio, "Sheela-Na-Gigs and Nancy Spero" (1999 December 2-2000 February 11), 1997-2000 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Michael Rosenfeld Gallery, 1995-2000 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Mills College, "True Grit: Seven Female Visionaries before Feminism" (2001 September 7-October 21) (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - The Montreal Museum of Fine Arts, "Global Village: The 60s" (2004 October 2-March 7), 2002-2004 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Mosaics, Glass, undated; 2001 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Munich Project, Stained Glass Mosaic, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Murals, undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Museu d'Art Contemporani de Barcelona [traveling show organized by MACBA], "Nancy Spero: Dissidances" (2008 July 3-September 29) (Box 13)
    - Contracts, 2007-2008 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 2007-2008 (Box 13, Folder 19-20)
    - Essays, 2008 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Exhibition List, 2008 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Framing, 2008 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Loan Forms, 2008 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Maypole Redux, 2008 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous, 2007-2008 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
    - Publicity, 2008; Includes 1 video disc (DVD) (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Wall Texts, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Museum Actions, undated; 1970s-1980s (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Museum In Progress, circa 1990s-2002; Includes 1 videocassette (VHS) (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Museum of Art and Archaeology, University of Missouri, Columbia, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Museum of Contemporary Art Los Angeles, 1988-2000 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Museum of Fine Arts Boston, Banners, undated; 2002-2003; Includes 1 videocassette (VHS) (Box 14, Folder 9-12)
  - The Museum of Modern Art, New York, 2007 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - The Museum of Modern Art, New York, Codex Artaud XXV, 1991-1992 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - The Museum of Modern Art, New York, Notes in Time, Gift of Ulrich Meyer, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Museum of Modern Art, Salzburg, "Nancy Spero: The Woman as Protagonist" (2009 February 21-June 14), 2008-2009 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Myth, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - National Academy of Design, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - National Endowment for the Arts and Harry N. Abrams, Inc. Book, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - National Gallery, Washington, D.C., 2008 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - National Gallery of Canada, 1995-2004 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - National Medal of Arts, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Neuberger Museum of Art, 1998-2000 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - The New Museum of Contemporary Art, 1970-2009; Includes 1 videocassette (VHS) (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - New Orleans Museum of Art, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - New York Kunsthalle, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Nielsen Gallery, 2003-2004 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Notes in Time, Master List, circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 28-29)
  - Notes in Time, Text References, circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Obrist, Hans-Ulrich, 1994-2008 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
  - Overtones Gallery, "Nancy Spero: Tattoo" (2005 September 10-October 22) (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Oxford University Press, Book Cover Image for Feminism by Sandra Kemp and Judith Squires, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Pacific Northwest College of Art, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Paris Trip, 2006 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Paula Cooper Gallery, Amnesty International Benefit, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Pelenc, Arielle, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, 2005-2006 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Phaidon Press Limited, 1994-1996 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Polak, Doran, 2003-2004 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Political Actions, circa 1980-2000 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Political Art Documentation and Distribution: The PADD Archives, Archival Activism by Lucy Lippard and The Other Side of the Coin: On Being Documentalists in an Activist Organization by Barbara Moore and Mimi Smith (1993 June-1994 May) (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Political Buttons, circa 1980s-2004 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Portland [Oregon] State Office Building Proposal, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Posner, Helaine, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - P.P.O.W., undated; 1995-2001 (Box 15, Folder 17-18)
  - "Presence of Greek Myth" (1998 May-June), Bagheria, Palermo (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - The Print Center, "Nancy Spero and Leon Golub: Prints 1950-2001" (2001 November 9-December 21) (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Printworks, 1998-2006 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Proimakis, Constantinos, 1991-1999 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Quebec, Galerie De L'UQAM, "The Spoken Image" (2001 May 9-June 23), 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Quotations and References, 1971-2001; 1965-2009 (Box 15, Folder 24-26)
  - Ramapo College, "Sheela Does Ramapo" (2001 February 3-March 23), 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Rape, undated (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Recommendations, 1970s-2008 (Box 15, Folder 29-31)
  - Reina Sophia, "Nancy Spero: Dissidances" (2008 October 10-2009 May 1) (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Residenzgalerie, "Nancy Spero and Leon Golub" (1995 August 13-December 3) (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Rhona Hoffman Gallery, 1984-2005 (Box 15, Folder 34-35)
  - Richard Anderson Fine Arts, 1993-1998; undated (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Ringling School of Art and Design, Subverting the Dominant Order: The Art of Nancy Spero" (2001 August 31-September 29) (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Rip Off File, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Rome, undated (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Roth/Horowitz Gallery, undated; 1979; 2000-2001; Includes 2 computer discs (3.5") (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Roth, Moira, circa 2001-2005 (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - Rutgers University, 2004-2006 (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - Sacred Heart University, The Gallery of Contemporary Art, 2008 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - "Saigon Open City: Liberation" (2006 November 26-2007 January 31) (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - A Sangra y Fuego, 1999-2000 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Santa Fe Art Institute, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Schlegal, Amy, 1997-2004 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - School of Visual Arts, 1984-1988 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - September 11 [2001], undated; 1988-2003 (Box 16, Folder 7-8)
  - Sheela Na Gig (published 1989-2001), 1991-2005; undated (Box 16, Folder 9-10)
  - Siglio Press, Torture of Women Book, 2007 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - "Skulptur-Figur Weiblich" (circa 1998) (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Sleigh, Sylvia, 2001-2006; 1973-1977 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - S. L. Simpson Gallery, 1984-1994 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Smith College Museum of Art, 1988-1990 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Smith, Kiki, 2004-2009; undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Smock Magazine, 2000-2003 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Snug Harbor Cultural Center, 2000-2001 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Solanas, Valerie -- "SCUM Manifesto", 1967-1977 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Sommerakademie, 1992-2000; Includes 1 videocassette (VHS) (Box 16, Folder 20-21)
  - Southern Graphics Council, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Space, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Spectra Color Project, circa 1980s (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Studio Stefania Miscetti, 1991-2009 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Technical -- Wall Painting for Permanent Installations, undated (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Terrain, 1988-1997 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Texte Zur Kunst, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Third Text, 1988-1995 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Thread Waxing Space, "Violence against Women" Discussion and Program, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - "Torture of Women" (1976 September 11-Octoper 6), Catalog Text, circa 1976 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - "Torture of Women" (1976 September 11-Octoper 6), Research and Reviews, circa 1970-1976 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Triangle Fire, circa 1990s (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Trinity College, "Nancy Spero: The Last Cigarette" (2002 October 30-December 6), 2001-2002 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - "True Grit: Seven Female Visionaries before Feminism" (2001-2004), Traveling Exhibition (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Tsunami Relief, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Turin, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - UNIFEM Fundraiser at United Nations, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - University of Massachusetts Dartmouth, "Nancy Spero: Selected Works from Codex Artaud, 1971-1972" (2001 November 3-December 13), 2000-2002 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - University of Pennsylvania, Institute of Contemporary Art, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - University of Rhode Island, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - University of Texas at Arlington, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - "Utopia Station" (2003), 2002-2004 (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - Vancouver Art Gallery, 1995-2002 (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - Venezuela, 1997-1998 (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - "Venice Biennale, 51" (2005 June 12-Novewmber 6) (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - "Venice Biennale, 52" (2007 June 10-November 21), 2006-2007 (Box 17, Folder 1-5)
  - "Vietnam -- U.S.A." (1990-1994) (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Visiting Artist Engagements, 1996-1997 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Visits/Talks, 1997-2005 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Von der Heydt-Museum, Wuppertal, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - "WACK! Art and the Feminist Revolution" (2007 March 4-July 7), The Museum of Contemporary Art Los Angeles, 2005-2006 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - "WACK! Art and the Feminist Revolution" (2008 October 4-2009 January 11), Vancouver Art Gallery, 2008-2009 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Walton High School Ceiling Proposal, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - War, circa 1982-circa 1990s (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - War Series, 2003; undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - "The Washington Print Club 19th Biennial" (2007 April 24-June 24) (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - "Water Works" (1998 May 24-September 30), R. C. Harris Filtration Plant, Toronto, 1988-1989 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Wayne State University, Elaine L. Jacob Gallery, "Contemporaries by Nancy Spero and Leon Golub" (1997 September 12-November 29) (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Weatherspoon Art Gallery, University of North Carolina at Greensboro, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Wesleyan University, Ezra and Cecile Zilkha Gallery, 1998-2003 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1999-2007; undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Who's Who in American Art and Other Directory Listings, 1986-2000 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Wildrich, Mechtild, 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Wilke, Hannah, 1992-1994 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Willard Gallery, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Williams College and Williams College Museum of Art, 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Women, 1970s-1990s (Box 17, Folder 26-33)
  - "Women and Children in Solidarity with the Afghan Women's Mission" (2001 November 2-25) (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Women: Appraisals, Dance and Active Histories, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Women Artists, 1970s-1990s (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Women Artists, Actions (published 1970-1988), undated; 1970-1977 (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - Women, Images (published circa 1950s-circa 2000s), undated; 1975-2002 (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
  - Women in Prison, undated; 1985-1993 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Women, Violence Against (published 1914-circa 1990s), 1970s-1980s; undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Women's Caucus for Art, 1975-2003; undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Women's Studies Research Center, Brandeis University, 2007 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - World Bank, Lobby Project Proposal, 1993-1994 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - The World Can't Wait, Drive Out the Bush Regime, 2005; Includes 1 video disc (DVD) (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Worldwide, University of California, San Diego, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Wynans, Franz -- Spero Collection for Canada, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 10-11)
  - York, Nora, 1990s; Includes 1 sound disc (CD); 2 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 18, Folder 12-13)
  - Zucker, Barbara, undated, 1996-2007 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Oversized Images (Source Material) from Box 11, Folder 16, undated (Box 29)
  - Oversized Codex Artaud Quotations Translated by Philip Golub from Box 9, Folder 3, circa 1970s (Box RD 30)
- Personal Business Records, circa 1976-2008; Series 6; 1 Linear feet Boxes 18-19
  Personal business records include many inventories of Spero's artwork including some for specific media. Also found are inventories of the Leon Golub Marital Trust and paintings by Golub. The gift record (photocopy) notes "Copy by Leon of Nancy's Gift Record* - Original lost in the 71st Street fire 1972-1973, *1969 to 1971-1972 is missing." Also found are records concerning reproduction permissions and fees, appraisals, consignments, and loans.
  This series is arranged by record type, and filed alphabetically by folder title.
  - Appraisal of Artwork by Spero, Insurance Values, 2008 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Consignment Agreements, 1991-2000; undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Gifts of Artwork (donated 1969-2003), 1988-2003; undated (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Inventories, Leon Golub Marital Trust, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Inventories, Nancy Spero (Box 18)
    - Artwork, undated; 1993-2003 (Box 18, Folder 20-21)
    - Available Works, circa 2001 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Drawings, circa 1980-1989 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Paintings, circa 1985-circa 1989 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Portfolios, Argon and Lists of Extra Prints and Missing Prints, circa 1989-circa 1990 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Prints, Intaglio and Etchings, circa 1987-circa 1990 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Prints, Large, circa 1980s-circa 1990 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Prints, Lithographs, circa 1987-circa 1990 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Prints, Lithographs, Earlier and Smaller Editions, circa 1988-circa 1989 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Prints, Tamarind, circa 1988-circa 1990 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - War Series, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Works 1979 and after, circa 1986-circa 1989 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Inventories, Leon Golub -- Paintings, circa 2000 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Invoices and Receipts, 1980s-2000 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Lists, Early Works, circa 1976-circa 1985 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Lists, Miscellaneous, 1990-circa 2001 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Lists, Sold Works, circa 2000s (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Loans, 1980s-1990s (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Mailing Lists, 1980s (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Photos and Slides Out, 1993-1998 (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - Prices, 1996-2005 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Reproduction Permissions and Fees, 1994-2008 (Box 19, Folder 1-3)
  - Sales, 1987-2005 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - System Subscriptions, ArtStacks and Connect, 1990s (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title Codes, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Works In, 1987-1989 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Works Out, 1987-2000 (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Printed Material, 1949-2009; Series 7; 6.1 Linear feet Boxes 19-25
  Printed materials consist of a wide variety of items including books, clippings, exhibition catalogs and announcements, periodicals, press releases, and reproductions. A high percentage are about Spero and/or reproduce her work. Some clippings and periodicals of a more general nature mention artists, exhibitions, social issues, and political movements of interest to Spero. This series includes a number of commercialy produced recordings: Tellis the Audio Cassette Magazine, #5 & # 6 Special Double Audio Visual Issue (1 sound cassette and pamphlet), as well as 20 videocassettes (VHS) and 2 sound discs (CD) about various subjects.
  Printed material is arranged by format and filed alphabetically by folder title. Exhibition catalogs, announcements and invitations have been sorted into the categories of Spero solo exhibitions, Spero group exhibitions, and other artists. Additional printed material is found with biographical materials (Series 1) and attached to correspondence (Series 2). Interviews with Nancy Spero and her published writings by her are filed with interviews and writings (Series 3 and Series 4, respectively). A wide variety of printed items are found in many subject files (Series 5),
  - Books, General, 1977-2001; undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Books with Spero Content, 2002; 1978 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Calendars and Schedules, 1972-2005 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1949-1988; undated (Box 19, Folder 12-30)
  - Clippings, 1989-2009 (Box 20, Folder 1-19)
  - Conference, Symposium, and Panel Discussion Announcements and Programs, 1984-2007; undated (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations - Spero Solo Exhibitions, 1958-1992; undated (Box 20, Folder 21-24)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations - Spero Solo Exhibitions, 1993-2008 (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations - Spero Group Exhibitions, undated; 1963-2009 (Box 21, Folder 3-6)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations - Other Artists, undated; 1974-2009 (Box 21, Folder 7-13)
  - Exhibition Catalogs - Spero Solo Exhibitions, 1979-2001 (Box 21, Folder 14-15)
  - Exhibition Catalogs - Spero Group Exhibitions, 1950-1976 (Box 21, Folder 16-20)
  - Exhibition Catalogs - Spero Group Exhibitions, 1978-1987 (Box 22, Folder 1-18)
  - Exhibition Catalogs - Spero Group Exhibitions, 1988-2005 (Box 23, Folder 1-10)
  - Exhibition Catalogs - Other Artists, 1973-2007; undated (Box 23, Folder 11-13)
  - Invitations, Miscellaneous Events, undated; 1982-2008 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Lecture Announcements, undated; 1988-1999 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Newsletters, undated; 1985-2007 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Periodicals, General, 1964-1979; undated (Box 23, Folder 17-21)
  - Periodicals, General, circa 1980s-2006; undated; Includes 1 sound cassette. (Box 24, Folder 1-4)
  - Periodicals with Articles about Spero, 1971-2006; undated (Box 24, Folder 5-9)
  - Periodicals with Reproductions of Spero's Work, 1971-1992 (Box 24, Folder 10-15)
  - Press Releases, 1970s-2009; undated (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Publication Announcements - Book, Print Portfolio, and Miscellaneous, 1994-2006 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Reproductions, Miscellaneous, 1989-circa 2009; undated (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Video Recordings, Various Subjects, circa 1990s-circa 2004; 3 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Video Recordings, Various Subjects, circa 1990s-circa 2004; 17 videocassettes (VHS); 2 video discs (CD) (Box 25, Folder 1-6)
- Photographic Material, 1940s-2009; Series 8; 1 Linear feet Boxes 25-26, 29
  This series consists of photographs and color digital prints; also found are slides, some negatives, and color transparencies. Images of artwork are mostly by Spero. Photographs of artwork by others include many unsigned works as well as pieces by Traude Linhardt, Mira Schor, and Ana Mendieta. Views of exhibition installations record Nancy Spero's solo exhibitions and her participation in the 2007 "Venice Biennale, 52." People appearing in photographs are Nancy Spero, Leon Golub, their sons, grandchildren, Nancy's sister Carol Newman, and unidentified people, most likely friends. Folders titled "family" and "friends" include views in which Spero and/or Golub are present. Miscellaneous subjects are a dog and owl. One photograph album, circa 2000s, consists of pictures that appear to have been taken on the same day; included are views of Nancy Spero with friends and family.
  Photographic materials are arranged by subject.
  - Artwork by Spero (Box 25)
    - Codex Artaud, 1972; undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Maypole Heads, Actor -- Yuksta, Untitled, circa 2000s (Box 25, Folder 8-14)
    - Miscellaneous (executed 1940s-1984), undated; 1978 (Box 25, Folder 15)